Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm 5863 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 4)
  - 0661. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 21. Maine and Maryland. 18 pages., 1918-1924; 19 (Reel 4)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Maine and Maryland; United States Department of Commerce cooperation with Department of Justice.
  - 0679. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 22. Massachusetts. 8 pages., 1917; 20 (Reel 4)
    People: George W. Anderson; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members in Massachusetts; private detective agencies.
  - 0687. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 23. Michigan. 60 pages., 1917-1921; 21 (Reel 4)
    People: Charles Moyer; Arnold Petersen; S. G. Bargery; William C. Fitts; William B. Wilson; Thomas W. Gregory; William D. Haywood; Woodrow W. Wilson; John W. Davis; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Communist party of America mass meetings; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Michigan; eviction of International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers organizers from Grand Rapids, Michigan; American Protective League; Department of Justice cooperation with local authorities; Socialist Labor party; Department of Justice raids; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor alleged strike plans of miners in Minnesota and Michigan.
  - 0747. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 24. Minnesota. 26 pages., 1917-1919; 22 (Reel 4)
    People: Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; Thomas C. Spelling; John Lind; Ambrose Tighe. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of deportation cases in Minnesota and Arizona; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; miners strikes; illegal liquor traffic; Department of Justice cooperation with authorities.
  - 0773. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 25. Mississippi. 3 pages., 23 (Reel 4)
    People: Not available. Subject: Citizen protest against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Mississippi. No date.
  - 0776. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 26. Missouri. 8 pages., 1918-1923; 24 (Reel 4)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Missouri; alleged general strike plans; Department of Justice prosecution of Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World defendants.
  - 0784. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 27. Montana. 147 pages., 1917-1932; 25 (Reel 4)
    People: A. Mitchell Palmer; A. M. Briggs; Burton K. Wheeler; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Montana; habeas corpus proceedings; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; American Protective League; state legislation relating to arson, sabotage, and criminal syndicalism during World War I; Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in coal and lumber industries.
  - 0931. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 28. Nebraska. 81 pages., 1917-1919; 26 (Reel 4)
    People: Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; Frank Little; William D. Haywood; William C. Fitts; Thomas S. Allen; George F. Vanderveer; Jane Street. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Nebraska; lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana; Industrial Workers of the World union organization; attempted plea bargain with Industrial Workers of the World Industrial Workers of the World defendants; Department of Justice raid on Industrial Workers of the World convention in Omaha; Industrial Workers of the World organization of domestic workers in Denver, Colorado, and Tulsa, Oklahoma.
  - 1012. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 29. Nevada. 11 pages., 1917-1920; 27 (Reel 4)
    People: A. Mitchell Palmer; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World strikes in Tonopah, Nevada, mining camps; wartime prosecution for unpatriotic remarks and utterances.
  - 1023. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 31. New Jersey. 12 pages., 1917-1920; 28 (Reel 4)
    People: L. A. Sterne. Subjects: American Federation of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in New Jersey; protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; Industrial Workers of the World organization of metal and machinery workers; United States Post Office Department censorship of mails.
  - 1035. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 32. New Mexico. 2 pages., 1917; 29 (Reel 4)
    People: Not available. Subject: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in New Mexico.
  - 1037. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 33. New York. 27 pages., 1917-1923; 30 (Reel 4)
    People: Louis Ratnofsky; William D. Haywood; a. Mitchell Palmer; J. Edgar Hoover; Francis Ralston Welsh; William C. Fitts; Charles W. Stockton. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in New York; Department of Justice raids; New York Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Industrial Workers of the World publications; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; Wells Fargo and Company cooperation with Department of Justice censorship; arrests of Industrial Workers of the World organizers.
  - 1064. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 33. Special Section, Bureau Papers Only. New York. 181 pages., 1920- 1921; 31 (Reel 4)
    People: L. J. Baley; George Hardy; J. Edgar Hoover; Charles Scully. Subjects: Military Intelligence Division informant reports on industrial unrest and Industrial Workers of the World activities in New York; strikes; union organization; mass meetings; publications; Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities among immigrants at Ellis Island; Industrial Workers of the World dissent with Comintern; convention of Hungarian-speaking members of the Industrial Workers of the World; private detective agencies.
  - 1247. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 13. Pages omitted after Frame 0293 of Reel 4. Idaho. 28 pages., 1917; 32 (Reel 4)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World publications; union organization.
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 5)
  - 0000. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 34. North Carolina. 4 pages., 1919; 1 (Reel 5)
    People: Not available. Subject: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in North Carolina.
  - 0004. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 35. North Dakota. 14 pages., 1917-1923; 2 (Reel 5)
    People: A. C. Townley; Kate Richards O'Hare. Subjects: Citizens and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans of agricultural workers in North Dakota; Farmers' Nonpartisan League of North Dakota.
  - 0017. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 35.Previously Restricted Materials. North Dakota. 2 pages., 1917; 3 (Reel 5)
    People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski. Subject: Farmers' Nonpartisan League of North Dakota. Frames 0017 and 0018 are repeated.
  - 0018. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 36. Ohio. 7 pages., 1917; 4 (Reel 5)
    People: William C. Fitts. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Ohio; protest against Department of Justice raids; private detective agencies.
  - 0025. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 37. Oklahoma. 76 pages., 1917-1921; 5 (Reel 5)
    People: A. Mitchell Palmer; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory; John L. Metzen. Subjects: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Oklahoma; Department of Justice investigation and prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World activities and pro-German matters in Oklahoma; Industrial Workers of the World General Defense Committee protest against events in Tulsa, Oklahoma, and Bisbee, Arizona; suppression of the Working Class Union in Oklahoma following alleged assassination attempt by four black members upon Seminole County officials.
  - 0101. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 38. Oregon. 129 pages., 1917-1918; 6 (Reel 5)
    People: William c. Fitts; Elmer Sandstrom; William d. Haywood; Thomas W. Gregory; Henry J. Weeks; Charles Warren. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers; Industrial Workers of the World protests against activities of the Loyal Legion of Loggers and Lumbermen; state and federal suppression of Industrial Workers of the World offices in Oregon; Industrial Workers of the World Official Membership Book and papers; censorship of Industrial Workers of the War publications; wartime shipbuilding and lumber worker strikes; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; arrest of Industrial Workers of the World members in Klamath Falls following acts of sabotage and anti-war activities; Department of Justice enforcement of Espionage Act.
  - 0230. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 39. Pennsylvania. 45 pages., 1917-1920; 7 (Reel 5)
    People: Charles Recht; Francis Fisher Kane; Claude r Porter; John Lord O'Brian; Alfred Bettman. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World Activities in Pennsylvania; Industrial Workers of the World publications; American Legion; request for return of Industrial Workers of the World papers and property seized in Department of Justice raids in Philadelphia; Military Intelligence Division and Naval Intelligence Division surveillance of labor conditions in Pittsburgh; Department of Justice raids in Philadelphia and Scranton.
  - 0275. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 41. Rhode Island. 9 pages., 1917; 8 (Reel 5)
    People: William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice raids in Rhode Island; inventory of Industrial Workers of the World and anarchist publications and papers seized in raids.
  - 0284. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 43. South Dakota. 8 pages., 1917; 9 (Reel 5)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against arson and Industrial Workers of the World activities in South Dakota; Agricultural Workers Industrial Union of the Industrial Workers of the World publications.
  - 0292. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 44. Tennessee. 4 pages., 1920; 10 (Reel 5)
    People: Not available. Subject: Request for information regarding Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities.
  - 0296. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 45. Texas. 13 pages., 1917-1923; 11 (Reel 5)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Texas; Industrial Workers of the World organization of Mexican-Americans.
  - 0309. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 49, Part 1. Washington. 230 pages., 1917-1918; 12 (Reel 5)
    People: William C. Fitts; Louis F. Post; Thomas W. Gregory; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; John Lord O'Brian; Thomas Tracy; Charles Warren; Newton D. Baker; Henry J. Weeks; Clarence L. Reames. Subjects: United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice suppression of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Washington; Industrial Workers of the World organization of immigrant labor, lumber workers, and agricultural workers; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Washington and Michigan; Council of National Defense; The Minute Men of Seattle, Washington; Department of Justice censorship of Industrial Workers of the World publications; United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice in prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership; Arizona State Federation of Labor protest against events in Bisbee, Arizona; United States Department of the Interior cooperation with Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World; mass meeting protest against lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank H. Little in Butte, Montana; Everett, Washington, massacre of Industrial Workers of the World members; Socialist party of Washington; Department of Justice cooperation with state suppression of Industrial Workers of the World; People's Council of America; Chamber of Commerce resolutions urging legislation to suppress strikes and criminal syndicalism; conference of state and federal prosecutors regarding Industrial Workers of the World cases; use of state militia in quelling industrial disputes; proposed declaration of martial law in Washington; arrest of Industrial Workers of the World members in Klamath Falls, Oregon.
  - 0539. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 49, Part 2. Washington. 260 pages., 1918; 13 (Reel 5)
    People: Thomas W. Gregory; Clarence L. Reames; George F. Vanderveer; Fred Lowery; Thomas J. Mooney; John Lord O'Brian; Claude R. Porter; A. S. Embree; William D. Haywood; Vincent St. John; Josephus Daniels; William C. Fitts; Leonard Foster; S. B. Phelan. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World member under immigration and deportation laws in Washington; habeas corpus proceedings; Industrial Workers of the World general strike plans; Military Intelligence Division surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice cooperation with state prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World members; conference of state and federal prosecutors; protest against California state prosecution of Mooney case; indictment of Industrial Workers of the World leadership for conspiracy to violate the neutrality laws; Seattle District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Bureau of Naval Intelligence cooperation with Department of Justice Industrial Workers of the World investigations in Washington and Alaska; Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers, cannery workers, and merchant marines; local police department raid on Industrial Workers of the World hall in Seattle; Bureau of Intelligence report on Industrial Workers of the World activities in Oregon; United States Army Department report on suppression of sedition and sabotage in the Northwest; United States Post Office Department cooperation with Department of Justice in censorship of Industrial Workers of the World publications; indictment of Industrial Workers of the World members for organizing among United States military forces; private detective agencies; Employers' Association of Washington; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities.
  - 0799. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 49, Part 3. Washington. 100 pages., 1918-1929; 14 (Reel 5)
    People: Harlan F. Stone; George F. Vanderveer; A. Mitchell Palmer; John Thomas Taylor; Ole Hanson; Clarence L. Reames; Fred Lowery; William C. Redfield; John Lord O'Brian; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers and cannery workers; protests against local police suppression of Industrial Workers of the World in Centralia, Washington; legal defense efforts; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Washington; American Legion; mass meetings; Loyal Legion of Loggers and Lumbermen; Industrial Workers of the World publications; state prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members; United States Department of Commerce cooperation with Department of Justice investigations of immigrant labor in fisheries of Washington and Alaska; state legislation against criminal syndicalism; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in the prosecution of immigration and deportation cases; habeas corpus proceedings; alleged illegal arrests by officers of the Bureau of Naval Intelligence.
  - 0899. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 50. West Virginia. 2 pages., 1919; 15 (Reel 5)
    People: Not available. Subject: Local prosecutor's request for Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in coal mines.
  - 0901. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 51. Wisconsin. 31 pages., 1914-1921; 16 (Reel 5)
    People: John Lord O'Brian; Roy Brown; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Military Intelligence Division cooperation with Bureau of Investigation; Citizens and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Wisconsin; Council of National Defense.
  - 0932. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 52. Wyoming. 5 pages., 1918; 17 (Reel 5)
    People: William C. Fitts. Subjects: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Wyoming; Council of National Defense.
  - 0937. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 54. Frank Little matter. 12 pages., 1917-1920; 18 (Reel 5)
    People: Frank Little; Burton K. Wheeler; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Local union, mass meeting, and citizen protests against lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana; Socialist party of America; alleged involvement of military personnel in lynching of Frank Little.
  - 0949. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 55. Industrial Workers of the World Legislation. 19 pages., 1917; 19 (Reel 5)
    People: William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United states Senate Judiciary Committee consideration of bills to restrict Industrial Workers of the World activities in the United States draft wartime legislation for public safety and against sedition.
  - 0968. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 56. Nolan Industrial Workers of the World Case, Western District of Washington. 32 pages., 1917-1918; 20 (Reel 5)
    People: Thomas Nolan; E. A. Matson; Robert Solen; Thomas Tracy; Louise Olivereau; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Washington; Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers; general strikes; alleged acts of sabotage.
  - 1000. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57, Part 1. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 147 pages., 1917-1921; 21 (Reel 5)
    People: Claude R. Porter; George N. Murdock; John W. Preston; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts; William D. Stephens; P. H. Johnson; Frederick H. Esmond; Theodora Pollok; Woodrow W. Wilson; Frank K. Nebeker; Louis F. Post; George F. Vanderveer. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against treatment of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in jail; assistant United States attorney criticism of the governor of California in the Sacramento Bee, alleging interference with Industrial Workers of the World prosecutions; California District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas, and Chicago, Illinois; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities.
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 6)
  - 0000. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57, Part 2. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 240 pages., 1918-1919; 1 (Reel 6)
    People: Claude R. Porter; Robert Duncan; Edward Anderson; John W. Preston; Thomas W. Gregory; George N. Murdock; Elbert Coutts; Theodora Pollok; Charles M. Fickert; Francis Ralston Welsh; Thomas J. Mooney; Frederick H, Esmond; John Lord O'Brian; Louis Connolly; William C. Fitts; William Hood. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against prosecution of Theodora Pollok; California District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; indictment of William Hood, et al.
  - 0240. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57. Previously Restricted Materials. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 46 pages., 1918-1921; 2 (Reel 6)
    People: Godfrey Ebel; Frederick H. Esmond; John Dymond; Mortimer Downing; Claude R. Porter; George N. Murdock; Elbert Coutts; Charles M. Fickert; Edward Anderson; Theodora Pollok; John W. Preston; P. H. Johnson; George F. Vanderveer; John Lord O'Brian; William E. Cavanaugh; Clarence Darrow; J. B. McNamara; J. J. McNamara. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports regarding prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against treatment of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in jail; Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas, and Chicago, Illinois; protests against prosecution of Theodora Pollok; investigation of Espionage Act violations in Los Angeles, California; alleged jury tampering by Clarence Darrow in the McNamara case.
  - 0286. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57, Part 3. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 70 pages., 1919-1930; 3 (Reel 6)
    People: William D. Mitchell; William F. Petersen; Frederick H. Esmond; Anna Kaufman; Annette Abbott Adams; Roger N. Baldwin; Albert DeSilver; Harry M. Daugherty; James H. Manning; Caroline A. Lowe; Joseph McCarty; Thomas J. Mooney; Edward Anderson; William L. Frierson; Frank M. Silva; A. Mitchell Palmer; Joseph Harper; Godfrey Ebel; Alexander S. Lanier; William D. Haywood; Roy Dempsey. Subjects: Request for access to Department of Justice files regarding prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; release of insane prisoner from Saint Elizabeth's Hospital; United States Supreme Court denial of writ of certiorari in case o Edward Anderson, et al.; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in deportation and immigration cases; protests against conviction of Industrial Workers of the World defendants; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; United States War Department censorship of mail of prisoners.